Customer discovery, because we're there,
now. Customer discovery, in my opinion,
for you now, is very important. What is
it? It actually comes from a book called
The Four Steps to Epiphany
by Steve Blank which came before Eric
Ries Lean Startup. If you haven't read
these books, or at least one of them,
you should.
Um
reading about it, or discussing with a
summary on ChatGPT, won't replace you
reading this, just so so you know. And
it will change
the way in which you perceive this whole
subject, and how to build products. With
AI, without AI, it doesn't matter.
Everything that they put here stands.
And there are things that cannot be
replaced
by AI in product management, and that's
customer discovery done right.
So again, a lot of startups fail from a
lack of market need,
and they do fail
quite fast if they don't especially if
they don't find the money.
Um
And why
why does it happen? Because as a best
practice, what you should do when
building a startup, and don't feel bad
now if you didn't do this yet, because
you can do this now, in one week. You
can do this with the deliverables that
we're going to ask for you. You're going
to be able to do this for your startup
starting tomorrow.
Usually you discover a market need.
Let's say you said that. You did that.
You usually define a hypothesis with
both need and proposed solution. So,
your pitches, your Lean Model Canvas
that's a hypothesis.
I know that there's that need or that
problem in the market for whomever, and
I do have this solution. This is a
hypothesis. This is not proven.
Until you discuss with customers and
validate it directly that someone will
pay for it in a way in which it makes
sense,
um you are not validating it. If the
market is big, if someone else did it,
blah blah, it doesn't matter. You need
to do it, and you need to validate this
through customer discovery with your
startup, with your idea, with your
solution, with your team. You should
complete customer research. So, this is
how customer discovery is done. Usually,
you do customer interviews, focus
groups, surveys.
You will see that I will suggest and the
deliverables will be customer
interviews. That's because you don't
You're not able to do focus groups
enough to prove a point like big
companies do. And surveys can be very
leading. That doesn't count as real
customer uh discovery for a product. So,
you really need to discuss face-to-face
with users. Usually, you analyze all the
data and information, and you uncover
insights. The insights might be uh very
painful for you because you might
invalidate your hypothesis, and you
should be happy if the hypothesis is
invalidated because at least now you can
focus on another hypothesis that might
be validated, and you wouldn't have
worked like a year of your life
investing into something that no one uh
will use.
And usually, you need to act on those
insights. So, um you should move on to
delight customers. And if you uh
invalidate your hypothesis, and that
specific thing, that specific solution,
that specific feature, whatever, doesn't
make sense because you need to do this
not only at the beginning of the
product, but all of the time when you
need to add something in it, then you
should move to something else. If it
doesn't uh delight uh users.